A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Rockefeller University Concerts FA879
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Rockefeller University Concerts
1959-1977
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA879
13.5 Cubic Feet 11 boxes
11 boxes. Boxes 10 and 11 are oversized.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 600-8
Biographical / Historical
In the fall of 1959 The Rockefeller University (formerly The Rockefeller Institute) under the inspiration and direction of Dr. Theodore Shedlovsky instituted a series of subscription concerts on Wednesday evenings and occasionally on Sunday afternoons. These became an established University event, well attended by faculty and students and frequently preceded by a buffet dinner in the Abby Aldrich Hall dining room. On Dr. Shedlovsky's death, along with his papers, the tapes of the concerts were given to the University archives.
Related Materials
Correspondence dealing with concert plans and arrangements are contained in the Theodore Shedlovsky papers.
Custodial History
Recieved or inventoried April, 1977.
Boxes 10 and 11 received October 25, 1983.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 25 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Chronological. Years are divided by the academic year (September-May)
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Contents of the collection are primarily audio tapes and reels.
Almost all the concerts were taped on 7 inch reels. In some instances duplicate tapes have already been made. Originals and duplicates are boxed together chronologically. In most instances there is a copy of the concert program in the tape box. Another set of programs is shelved with the tape collection.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: concert programs.
Genetics; China; Biology -- Research; Medical care; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medical research; DNA; Medicine, Preventive; Vivisection; Medical sciences
- 1959/1960; 1960/1961; 1961/1962 (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
- 1962/1963; 1963/1964 (Box 2)
- 1964/1965; 1966/1967 through December (Box 3)
- 1966/1967 from January 4; 1967/1968 (Box 4)
- 1967/1968; 1968/1969 (Box 5)
- 1969/1970; 1970/1971 to February 17 (Box 6)
- 1970/1971 from February; 1971/1972 (Box 7)
- 1972/1973; 1973/1974 (Box 8)
- 1974/1975; 1975/1976 (Box 9)
- Concert programs (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Wednesday, 1976 October 20-Wednesday, 1977 April 13, 14 tapes (Box 10)
  Scope and Contents note
  Tapes lacking for following concerts [See photocopy of attached letter dated August 3, 1977. Stephen Szabo / Ilse Naumann.]
  Includes:
  James Tocco - pianist (no program) October 6, 1976
  Theodore Lettvin - pianist (no program) December 1, 1976
  Pasternak / Newbold - piano and clarinet (program in Box no (10) 1) January 5, 1977
  NY Chamber Soloists (program in Box no (10) 1) January 19, 1977
  Jacob Lateiner - pianist (program in Box no. (10) 1) March 16, 1977.
- 1977 April 24-27, 3 tapes (Box 11)